Often when I look at what people are
building out there, it's just like,
"You're not quite getting it." Like, you
know, if you were just like pushing
yourself and just really imagining like
all of this being roughly 10 times
better than it is today, you know, like
in a year, but you would build in a
different way.
>> What do you think people aren't pricing
in in terms of where things are going?
>> The majority of actions on the internet
will be taken by agents. If you want
your product to be successful for
agents, you have to build, you know, for
a certain level of scale.
>> How many agents do you find yourself
running in parallel just uh in the in
your kind of your day-to-day work?
>> As I'm pushing the frontier, I find
myself like building larger and larger
teams of agents. And then when we have
the next breakthrough with models, like
suddenly it's just like I'm like, "Oh,
well, you know, a bigger agent can just
do all of it." And so I kind of shrink
the team again. And then it just kind of
goes through this expansion and
shrinking expansion.
>> It kind of makes me think about there's
this whole loops thing and then this
whole graphs thing.
>> Having to set up and fiddle with your
loops is something that maybe people got
excited about, but I don't think this is
the way that it's going to work. Over
time, you just want to system that
learns. You don't want to necessarily
think about how I'm just like, "I'm
going to loop it exactly this way in
order to get good results."
>> there's still more radical change
happening to how we work?
>> to continue to change quite radically.
Even today, it still feels like a bit
clunky, and I think it will feel clunky
until it isn't.
>> I mean, Evo, thank you for doing this.
>> Yeah.
Big fan of you.
>> Of course.
>> Uh
>> Nice room.
>> You launched uh a ton of stuff today.
How how did your sleep? How are you
sleeping? Are you doing all right?
>> I'm doing great. I'm fortunate to have a
very good team.
>> Mhm.
>> So, while I sleep, they were
awake most of the night. We have this
amazing room uh at the office called the
library, which we completely repurposed
as like a mega war room. And the vibes
in there are just immaculate. Uh
people were there until like very, very
late.
>> So, you've been a long-time engineer.
Are you are you coding at all anymore?
Are you shipping PRs? Are you mostly
like in docs and in meetings now?
>> What is coding?
>> Exactly.
Yeah. Are you shipping PRs? I don't
know. Is that
>> Uh Yeah, yeah, yeah. Merch Merging some
code every once in a while. Technically,
like a lot of code is getting written
for me to do all sorts of kinds of like
analysis, like you know, understand like
trends, understand a business,
understand the next feature, you know,
how well our previous launches are
doing. A lot of code is written by Codex
for dot. You know, I'm obviously not
writing it by hand anymore.
Occasionally, at the in during the
weekends, I'll have like a little
therapeutic moment where I do a little
lead code just by hand. Um but that's
the only actual hands-coding that I do.
>> How many agents do you find yourself
running in parallel just uh in the in
the kind of your day-to-day work?
>> I used to run a lot more in parallel and
then we were, you know, fortunate enough
to get um a breakthrough with ultrafast.
And so, now, you know, I feel like you
know, I'm able to be in the flow again
and so it's just having a faster agent
helps me a lot. I'm excited that we're
getting, you know, 6-month-old ultrafast
out there soon. Um and then, yeah, I
think it's it's it sort of varies. Um as
I'm kind of like pushing different here,
I find myself like, you know, building
larger and larger teams of agents. And
then, when we have the next breakthrough
with models, like suddenly it's just
like I am like, oh, well, you know, a
bigger agent can just do all of it and I
keep everything in memory and learn. And
so, I kind of shrink the team again. And
then, it just kind of goes through this
like expansion and shrinking expansion.
>> Hm, okay. Can you say more about that?
It kind of makes me think about there's
this whole loops thing and then this
whole graphs thing. Is like an evolution
of that in some way or
>> I think like having to set up and fiddle
with your loops and, you know, figuring
that out is something that, you know,
maybe people got excited about, but I
don't think this is the way that it's
going to work. I think the way that it's
going to work is a what
how we're positioning and and what we're
shipping with dots, where you have an
incredibly smart agent that works 24/7,
understands your goals, understands your
preferences, learns from feedback. Um
and, you know, it's like what we
launched is like, no, perfect. I will
learn very much from, you know, making
this available to our pro users. But
over time, just want a system that
learns from, you know, what you want to
achieve. You don't want to necessarily
think about hours like I'm going to loop
it exactly this way in order to get
results. So, right now there's Codex,
there's ChatGPT work, there's ChatGPT
consumer, there's dots. What I'm hearing
is you think we're heading towards dots
kind of being the primary way you talk
to AI, and that kicks off all these
other things.
>> Yeah, I think fundamentally if you take
a step back and, you know, whether it's
dots or not, um it's all about breaking
free from the technology
um and
having this sort of like permanent
active intelligence that knows, you
know, everything it needs to do
and is available through any client, any
screen. You can call it, you know, like
maybe you walk into a meeting room, it
shows up in the meeting, it takes notes,
you know, you pick it back up on email,
um and then, you know, you text it if
you need it. It's not that, you know,
you need to be glued to a laptop or, you
know, you're like always on your phone.
It's just like it's available when you
need it and then it's also like gets out
of the way when you don't need it. And I
can't wait, you know, for that to sort
of like come to fruition because I think
like just carrying your laptop as like
this brick around everywhere is just
like, you know, you're kind of like tied
to the technology instead of the
technology working for you.
>> This episode is brought to you by our
season's presenting sponsor WorkOS. What
do OpenAI Anthropic, Cursor, Replit,
Sierra, Clay, and hundreds of other
winning companies all have in common?
They are all powered by WorkOS. If
you're building a product for the
enterprise, you felt the pain of
integrating single sign-on, SCIM, RBA,
audit logs, and other features required
by large companies. WorkOS turns those
deal blockers into drop-in APIs with a
modern developer platform built
specifically for B2B SaaS. Literally
every startup that I'm an investor in
that starts to expand upmarket ends up
working with WorkOS. And that's because
they are the best. Whether you are a
seed stage startup trying to land your
first enterprise customer or a unicorn
expanding globally, WorkOS is the
fastest path to becoming enterprise
ready and unblocking growth. It's
essentially Stripe for enterprise
features. Visit workos.com to get
started or just hit up their Slack where
they have actual engineers waiting to
answer your questions. WorkOS allows you
to build faster with delightful APIs,
comprehensive docs, and a smooth
developer experience. Go to workos.com
to make your app enterprise ready today.
I was going to ask you about this. It
feels like so much has changed in how we
work over the past like 2 years. In 2
years, especially engineers, but a lot
of roles have just the role your
day-to-day life has changed
significantly.
And I'm curious if you think we're kind
of settling into what work will look
like in the next, I don't know, 5 years?
Let's say 2 years, that's feels way too
far to think about. Or do you think
there's still more radical change
happening to how we work in
>> No, I think it's going to continue to
change
quite radically. Even today,
you know, it does seem like the
technology is finally coming together
with voice, uh you know, multimodal
inputs, outputs, but it still feels like
a bit clunky and I think it will feel
clunky until it isn't. And then you're
just like, "Wow, you know, it's like
I can just talk to this thing the same
way that we're talking right now. It
just remembers things perfectly. If
I want to, you know,
ideate and brainstorm, I can just like,
you know, squiggle a thing. I have this
collaborative surface. You know, this is
what we launched with ChatGPT spaces
signal to various startup dot. You know,
you can imagine we have like a shared
whiteboard, we can collaborate between
humans, between agents. And I think it's
going to sort of like transcend
conversations, transcend, you know, like
a lot of the clients that you have
today. And like, none of this is just
really working today, right? So, I think
that we're going to go through this big
new transformation. What I'm hearing
here is dots is a big part of that
future, this AI assistant that just kind
of does everything for you and you don't
have to think about Codex versus ChatGPT
and
>> Yes, and for Codex and ChatGPT, we're
going to merge uh like the the we have
we have chat, we have the work toggle.
Like you know, we heard the feedback
loud and clear. Like you know, people
love the capability in work, but then
also you know, you're like sometimes you
want to use chat because it's a little
bit faster. And you know, more pleasant
to use. And so we're we're merging that.
We're reducing that complexity.
Eventually, we will ship all of the
capabilities of Docs, you know, straight
into ChatGPT as well and you know, lift
the floor
for like our 1.2 billion users, which
you know, at that time we'll see like
how many we have. Um and we want it to
be really really seamless. One thing
that I'm very excited with with Docs is
like they don't have a model picker.
There's just no configuration. You just
talk to it. Like the only thing that you
have to configure is like which channels
you want to
talk to.
>> It feels very much like the Her kind of
vision of the world. I don't know. Do
you think about that movie much? Just
this idea of this
>> I watched it once.
Yeah. I think it's it's it's
interesting, you know, to to to think
about, you know, maybe more what what I
think about more is like, you know,
sci-fi from from, you know, 30 40 years
ago and like how visionary it was.
>> Is there specific sci-fi you think about
that's most influenced you?
>> Like you know, books like Neuromancer
and then you know, the original like
Star Trek.
Um you know, I think about that a lot.
And there's something about Star Trek
which I think, you know, was like there
was this technology that was like very
very useful. Obviously like, you know,
you were able to just like talk to a
computer and like it does things for
you. Like you can talk to your spaceship
and it just moves, right? It's like this
is getting real, you know, like we're
entering that era.
>> So we're recording this in front of a
live audience. There was this line out
the door just people waiting to see you,
to hear from you.
How do you just think about this, I
don't know, role you're in, this
responsibility you have to build what
you're building and the impact it has on
people's lives. I don't know. Just what
does that feel like? How do you think
about that?
>> I think it's very important to be part
of a community and to
build with people. It was like, you
know, we're we're discovering this
technology and like what we can do
together.
Um and so every time I you know, talk to
people, I'm like I'm kind of like
reminded of you're doing this thing
which I hadn't even anticipated. You
know, it's impacting your life in a
certain way and it's impacted like you
know, this other person's life and then
it's just like all together. It's both
very humbling, very inspiring, and I
think very necessary in order to build
something that is truly useful for
humans. I I don't know how we would do
it without the community.
>> That's something I hear a lot with
people building an AI is they don't know
what it is until they've launched it and
they see how people use it, see what
emerges. And it feels like kind of what
you're saying is just build it with
people versus like here's the vision,
we've got it figured out.
>> Even the Twitter community has been very
nice in general.
>> You're very good at Twitter.
Kind of antagonistic sometimes, but very
good. How do you How do you find time to
even tweet? I don't understand how
someone in your role has time to sit on
Twitter, tweet, reply.
>> I spend like maybe half an hour per day.
Yeah, just say rolling and then doing
something when I feel inspired and I
have something interesting to say. Often
it just comes like in the moment. Yeah.
>> Perfect Twitter skill.
>> And I have a
We haven't released the dot
the the the team dots yet, but you know
today we're releasing the primary dot
which you can configure, you can get
used to like what a dot can do, connect
it to your apps.
But we'll release
the ability to create more than one. And
so I have one that's responsible for
Twitter.
>> Okay, say more about that. So right now
everyone gets one dot.
>> Yeah.
>> Right now they can't add more dots.
>> That's right.
>> They will be able to have many dots.
Talk about kind of where that's going.
>> Yeah, so we wanted to start with one,
the primary dot which is the one that
you know, you'll probably also text that
you know, learns your preferences most
deeply as well and kind of see like you
know, what people do with it, see how we
need to tune the system, you know, learn
that working with the community and then
very quickly soon you'll be able to add
you know, a second one, a third one, a
fourth one, as many as you need to
create like your virtual team. And then
you can give them specific roles, right?
Is it It's not I don't find it
absolutely necessary, but sometimes I
have like a thing that is requires quite
a bit of work, you know, such as like
monitoring like Twitter for me. And then
you know, that's It's a thing is like
like, this will be like so much work
that is like the work of an entire dot.
Um and then you know, you can have a
couple of those.
>> So if you think about all the launches
that happened today, it feels like dots
maybe like the sexiest.
I'm curious if there's something that
you think is not getting the attention
it probably deserves that will become a
really, really important down the road
that's kind of people are sleeping on
that's like a vision.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah, important.
>> the sleeper hit is ecosystem. So opening
it all up. Uh and the commitment, the
deep commitment we have towards opening
it all up. So we have signing with
ChatGPT 16 partners. Very, very proud of
that. Like we started that like really
it was sort of like in the moment last
year. Um I was talking to creators of Pi
and open code and it was like, of
course, you know, you should just be
able to use the critics
sign on and then you know, you use the
usage and then you just we kind of like
shook hands, you know, like virtually
we're like, you know, it's just like use
this this uh this off um and then you
know, kind of trust you to not do
anything shady. You know, that grew
obviously that became quite popular and
then you know, now we made it, you know,
an actual thing that was supported with
many, many partners. Um and I'm excited
to grow that very quickly. You know, the
other side as well is like opening up
all of the infrastructure and how we
build for ChatGPT, you know, with
plug-in extensions, also plug-in
discovery, just allowing, you know,
everyone to ship something through like
maybe 1.2 billion users, right? You
know, and benefiting from that
distribution. And we also have shared
economics um that we didn't actually
talk uh in the keynote, but you know, we
will pay, you know, our plug-ins that
are
uh popular and you know, are seeing a
lot of usage. Uh they're going to get
part of like the the revenue share as
well. Uh and so I think this commitment
towards an open ecosystem is going to be
very exciting.
>> That's amazing. Uh okay, so as an
example, so say Notion, somebody's using
the Notion plug-in or the Figma plug-in
within
uh ChatGPT work, Notion, Figma make
money from people using it within the
app.
>> Yes, so um we have, you know, all these
subscribers that use ChatGPT, um they
get like, you know, a certain amount of
usage and then when have that, the when
when the users use that usage with the
plugin, or within the other product when
they use sign-in with ChatGPT, um you
know, we will have like some shared
economics with them where they will get
to remunerate.
>> One of the, I don't know, things I think
that gets people excited about plugins
and ecosystems is distribution
platforms, ways to kind of get out
there. People discover my app, it blows
up.
>> any advice for people that want their
plugins to, you know, bubble up, to get
discovered?
>> Build a good plugin.
>> Yeah.
>> The way that it works and we'll
obviously tune uh the system, but we
look at retention uh numbers, uh we look
at
um you know, how successful the plugin,
the quality, and then you know, that's
what we then start to recommend to users
uh in conversations. And so, your plugin
can just like you know, get recommended
to like you know, a significant slice of
users. Obviously, if your plugin is not
quite good, they will stop being
recommended.
>> Right. That's amazing that you're
looking at retention of people using
that plugin. That's right. Um is it is
it actually adding utility? Is it, you
know, enabling ChatGPT to do something
else?
>> Got it. So, it's it's not so much an AEO
kind of get the right words and get
people writing about you. It's people
using it consistently, sticking with it.
That's right. I think. Okay, so you
think that's kind of the sleeper hit
that's going to become a big deal. And I
know this is kind of the second attempt.
You guys had an app marketplace that
This one is the right one. Okay, this is
This one's going to work. Maybe going
back to dots cuz it feels like that's a
big part of the vision in the future.
When did you guys start working on this?
Obviously, there's a open claw, a big
open claw moment. You guys Peter joined
and there There's a foundation,
uh and then Grok Bot, Muse, and
Instinct, and all these things. I guess
how long have you guys been working on
it? Why did it take so long for you guys
to get something out?
>> Do you remember a Codex Cloud?
>> Yeah, the first uh yeah.
>> That was like a year ago, right? And uh
if you look back at Codex Cloud and you
look at the little animation that we
used, uh I think that was the
inspiration for Grok Bot.
>> Um
>> Yeah. It's just like very, very similar.
>> Yeah, really similar, I would say.
>> But, you know, seriously, like on the
research, long, persistent, long horizon
task, this is something that we've
worked on, you know, for more than 2
years. Memory systems, that's like
coherent, you know, like roughly the
same amount of time. We launched a lot
of that straight into ChatGPT. I think,
you know, people just really enjoy that
ChatGPT gets to know, like, you know, so
much relevant information about you. So
many people I talked to have like an
anecdote of like, "Hey, you know, I fell
ill and, you know, ChatGPT remembered
actually, like, you know, I had this
barbecue
and, you know, I had like lime and I was
like making tequila and like, you know,
it was just like probably like this burn
that I have on my hand is actually like
this lime, you know, it's like in some
burn." And he's just like, "How did it
know that?" And it's like, you know,
it's just the memory works very, very
well in ChatGPT. And so, we've put a lot
of research in that. And, you know, all
of this coming together on top of like
the Quora harness and also the ability
to just like run 24/7 with, you know,
good productivity. That's what we
launched with dots. And so, it's the
work of like many, many months. And
then, one of the important things was
also getting safety and security right.
You know, this is also why we launched
with Astra, it's our safest, most
aligned model. And like a lot more
effort went into like making dots, like,
you know, just really safe and secure.
>> A question I like to ask people who come
on the podcast is, where do you think
human brains will continue to be
valuable over time? Where do you find
yourself being necessary in the work
that happens versus where AI is taking
on more and more? Where do you think
human brains will continue to be useful,
most useful over time?
>> Yes, I I think this is very much a
function of how we build the technology
in the way that we design everything at
OpenAI is like to put humans at the
center of it and build it as extensions
of humans of of of your will and your
taste. And so, just really be like this
super empowering thing.
Um, I think as long as we continue to do
that and it kind of like enables you to
just take whatever you wanted to do and,
you know, your creativity and your taste
and sort of like, you know, expand that,
you know, in in a way that feels like
awesome in the moment. It's just like
really this artistic tool, right? And we
may we may not have coders anymore, but
we have more builders than ever. And I
think there's something that's going to
remain, I I know, human about that. Like
humans want to learn and see, you know,
what other humans are building and you
know, I'm like much more interested I'm
here I'm you know, I'm not talking to
Dot you know, I'm talking to you, right?
I think that will remain true for like a
very very long time.
>> One of the things that has emerged with
engineers especially is in in how their
lives have changed is there's a lot more
context switching. There's kind of this
trend of loneliness that has emerged
where they're talking to agents all day
instead of other humans. I'm curious how
much you think about just like that part
of the
of the impact AI has on people's lives
and just how you might Is there
solutions to that? Is there stuff you
think about to make that less annoying?
>> Yes, all the time. Reducing, you know,
configuration fatigue is, you know, one.
Um reducing the fact that talking to an
agent is like sort of like a solo
adventure and you just have this, you
know, conversation just with with your
one agent and then, you know, you have
like many and then you're delegating so
many things.
A lot of things are going to come
together
to make it a
much more delightful and something that
I spend a lot of time the team spend a
lot of time thinking about. So, I think,
you know,
>> For me, the ideal way to get things done
is, you know, would be like to just have
it in your physical space. You know,
we're just having conversation like we
have now. It's able to sort of like, you
know, observe, you know, like hear the
ideas that we have. We can, you know,
jot something down in a white paper on a
on a paper, you know, I can maybe like,
you know, take that and you know, start
building in the background and then
you're like, you know, actually have
another idea and then you just like it
starts building another thing. You can
just project it on a screen and then you
just talk to it and it's just evolving
in a conversation, you know, with other
humans and you don't have this fatigue
of like having to be like, you know, on
this like screen and you're just like,
you know, thinking about prompting. It's
just like becomes like super natural.
That's what we're trending towards, you
know, I think
we didn't fully get there today, but you
know, we'll get there in the future.
>> One of the other kind of downsides
that's emerged along those lines is just
this kind of pressure to do more because
we can do more. Everyone's just like,
come on, run 30 agents at once. Why
aren't you
shipping more? Everyone's shipping more.
Do you think that's solvable? Do you
think that's just kind of, I don't know,
human nature? We can do more, let's do
more. Something there.
>> I think we we we heard Sam as well, you
know, about the promise of of this as
well, which is
reduced the noise and
you know, allow you to spend attention
where you want to spend attention and
you know, having like all these things
that
you know, like maybe you know, maybe
important and maybe not important but
they're kind of vying for your attention
and it's just sort of like
tone that down a little and you know,
just get you to focus on on on the
things.
I find it remarkable like every time I
go on a holiday and you know, I I I I
take that one week uh to just fully
disconnect like you know, I start to
thinking like different and more
creative ways. And I'm very eager to see
like you know, can we bring that? You
know, can we just make this your
day-to-day like you know, maybe you need
fewer meetings. You know, maybe you
don't need you know, to do as much and
you know, you would actually be more
productive if you're like you know,
better rested. And so you know, we will
have to you know, I think as an industry
figure that out. Um but I think that's
the promise of AI and it's not you know,
just
one more prompt you know, per second.
>> There's a bot that I'm building right
now that's kind of this energy audit bot
that watches my calendar and asks me
just like was this giving energy taking
away energy? Is it something someone
else could have done? I feel like you
know, AI should be like hey Lenny, maybe
maybe you can cut out these things so
you could be a happier person. Is there
anything you've done really
interestingly with AI recently that's
just like a really cool use case of wow,
that really was amazing. It blew my mind
or someone you've heard.
>> I can do was like something cool because
the the live demo just failed, right?
You know, in front of everyone. So there
there was like okay, well, it's not so
cool. But actually uh my my my daughter
was you know, it's like realized I was
you know, I defected like you know, we
have chat GPT production um went down
and so it pinged me 5 minutes before the
live demo.
Which was actually quite stressful
because it was like hey, production is
down. And uh it's like oh well, you
know, it's like do you want me to try
and fix it? And I'm like um I don't
think you're there yet, you know, little
dot but you know, thank you for trying
and then you know, then you know, I got
in touch with like the engineering teams
and we started to look, you know, what
was going on and you know, they did it's
like fixed by now.
But,
having this thing that just understands
like
okay, there's a pretty important thing
happening. It's called DevDay. There's
like this production system. There's a
live demo. It's probably using this
production system. So, these two are
things are connected and this is
happening in 5 minutes. So, I should
ping him because like he probably wants
to know about it. I think that's quite
remarkable.
That is remarkable. Wow. So, it just
knew that this was coming and told you.
And I love that it wanted to fix it and
you were like, not quite. You're not
quite there yet. I don't think here's
like, you know, please go impress me,
but you know, that would have been a
better story. How do you feel about just
giving access to all these things? I
don't know. Like did does it have access
to the production code base and like,
you know, It has access to some some of
production systems with guardrails.
You know, so we we built We talked about
specialist dots, but specialist dots are
just like operated with additional
guardrails, additional monitoring, and
then, you know, on their own hardware.
So, we actually run some on Mac minis.
The fundamental difference in the way
that we've built dots is like the
harness does not run on the machine.
You know, and then this is like maybe
people have not realized is like it can
connect to as many devices as you want.
So, it has its own computer. You can
actually connect it to your own laptop
as well. Over time, you might connect it
to like 10 different devices and it can
control it all. A little bit like an
octopus. So, you're basically talking
your dot, it's living in some VM
somewhere and it can Yeah. Might be a
VM, might not be a VM. It's just like
it's a thing, you know, and it can
connect to many devices.
>> This season's supporting sponsor is DX.
Now that everybody at your company is
finally using AI, the question that
engineering leaders face is no longer
are we using AI, but is it paying off?
With DX, you can measure and benchmark
the impact of AI adoption across your
full product life cycle. DX shows you
where AI is helping developers and where
it's creating new bottlenecks. You can
also use it to evaluate AI vendors,
monitor costs and licenses, and see
exactly what's limiting your agents.
That's why hundreds of enterprises,
including Snowflake, Sony, and BNY, use
the DX platform to measure AI's impact
on developer productivity. Visit
getdx.com/lenny
to get a demo of DX. That's
getdx.com/lenny.
So, they're really hiring a lot. I know
you're hiring a lot.
In your interviewing, what have you seen
as skills that are kind of trending up
in what you look for that is more and
more important in people being
successful now? And what skills do you
find are trending down that are just
like, okay, we don't need that as much?
>> Yeah, I would say that skill that is
trending down is typing fast. No, that
is not that useful anymore. Skills that
are trending up is, you know, just great
taste, um thinking about the user,
connecting to the audience that you're
building for.
Um a lot of X founders are incredibly
successful right now or like you know,
there's like repeat founders. We're also
finding this like you know, when we're
hiring at OpenAI, like you know, we have
a lot of founders. I think we have more
than 120 XYC founders now currently at
OpenAI. So, it's like this mega startup.
And I think just this um this passion
and this envy to build something that
matters and then know what good looks
like is more important than ever. I've
been arguing for a long time that PMs
are kind of going to thrive in this time
because that's basically the job of a
PM. Uh you know, they're like, where
should we build? Help someone build it.
And then is this right? Is this great?
And iterate. So, uh I don't know. I
agree with that.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> Yeah, also roles are blurring. So, you
know, you might you might have been, you
know, only into design or only an
engineer and um you know, felt always a
little bit uncomfortable, but you know,
now it's just like it's your time to
shine.
>> Do you miss the engineering part of the
job? I I was an engineer back in the
day. I was an engineer for 10 years.
Little did you know. And you know,
there's this flow state. There's this
beauty of just building and just seeing
it work and not work. Yeah. Do you kind
of missed out at all, or you're just
like, "Okay, this is my old life."
>> I
I I missed out for for a while, and then
now with, you know, really fast speeds,
I'm finding that back.
Uh and so, I'm like really excited to
democratize that
uh as much as much as possible. It will
take a while for it to be like, you
know, absolutely ubiquitous, right? And
like, you know, available to like more
than a billion users.
But now, you know, with with ultra-fast
speeds, like we're able to achieve it
for a 6-month sole is like, you know,
like costs roughly the same as Astra.
And so, the progress there is like quite
astonishing, you know, even even for us
internally. We're like, "Wow, you know,
we can do these things." Also because we
are using Astra, and we're finding, you
know, like we we can push it super far.
And when you have those speeds, and
especially when you can able to like
voice control it, you know, you kind of
get back into this like really creative
state of mind and endless flow. It is
different from the flow of the past the
past, um but I don't miss it.
>> Yeah, it's like your last you launched
videos, just people kind of standing
around talking to their AI and just
cooking or
>> That's right.
>> sitting on a lounge chair.
>> Yeah. I asked people while I was kind of
walking around the the event what to ask
you, and one thing that came up a few
times is advice for new grads, kind of
people junior in their career.
I think a lot of people look up to you.
They want to be the next Thibault. What
advice do you have for folks kind of
early in their career in terms of what
to work on, what skills to build, what
to do?
Yeah. I think the next Thibault is
already at OpenAI. Uh his name is Ahmed
Ibrahim. I love working with him. He was
a new grad uh when he was hired at
OpenAI.
He's now responsible for all of OpenAI
compute fleet and applied
uh which is a massive massive
responsibility. I've built a lot of the
Codex harness. And the thing that has
made Ahmed um really stand out and
successful is just his
He's incredibly kind. He's incredibly
collaborative and always, you know,
tries to solve the problem that is like
really important, um but like, you know,
a way that, you know, he's not putting
himself first. And he is just a sponge.
He's like learning so fast and learning
about everything, and you know using all
of the latest technology to you know
learn at you know speeds I haven't seen
before.
Um and so he just in the span of like
you know a couple of months and and and
a year, you know, it's like his progress
uh at the company was just absolutely
fascinating to see. Uh he's now someone
I trust a ton uh in doing like you know
the the the most gnarly launches at
OpenAI. All right, I got to get him on
the podcast.
>> You should. You should. So kind of
thinking about how things work at
OpenAI, what would surprise people about
what it's like to work inside OpenAI?
From the outside it feels like it's just
like constant shipping code, things are
kind of like, you know, chaotic but
awesome. I don't know. What would
surprise people about what it's like
inside at OpenAI?
>> I don't know if that's surprising but it
is, you know, as I said, a lot of
ex-founders um doing a lot of
bottoms-up, you know, very exciting uh
ideas. You know, for example, decisions
API, you know, came together very
quickly. We realized like we have a
really good model with Luna. Uh we can
just do some, you know, constraint
sampling and then, you know, have it,
you know, shipped as like a different
shape to the responses API and then um
you know, when we do that uh it, you
know, it's like it's faster. It's quite
delightful so for some cases and it's
just if you were to like peel under the
hood, you realize like, okay, there's a
Slack channel that came together. Um you
know, initially it was like four people
kind of hacking on it on a weekend and
then it was made as accessible as like,
you know, company food and then people
got excited, started to build things and
they're like, "Oh, this is, you know, we
can support visual inputs. Like this is,
you know, even better than whatever is
out there." And then, you know, people
get more and more excited. People start
pitching in. And the way that is like,
you know, feels completely unstructured
and then um you know, take it all the
way and like, you know, ship something.
And then uh we try to hold like a high
bar for, you know, the quality and then
you know, stop things, you know, before
they go out or like, you know, maybe
they need a little bit more baking.
There's many more things that, you know,
we were maybe going to ship today at
DevDay and then we're like, "Okay, like
I was like I think this is a a already.
Let's kind of hold it back a little bit
and you know, space it out. So, we'll
have more launches next week and and and
and the week after. But, it's just this
incredible like bottoms-up energy and
then, you know, people kind of assuming
roles to kind of channel that in
productive ways.
>> Something that's very clear and unique
about OpenAI is it feels like you have a
lot of autonomy.
You're just like pressing the reset
button whenever you want. You're just
saying things on Twitter. Uh it feels
like a really unique culture where you
have a lot of autonomy and I imagine
there comes a lot of trust. Maybe you
can speak to just how that cuz I feel
like that's an advantage at OpenAI. It
allows you to move faster, just that
cultural philosophy.
>> You got a lot of autonomy and then, you
know, you have to just own up to it. You
so, you know, we just kind of trust
people to make great choices.
And then, you know, when things go
wrong, uh you know, fix fix it quickly
or, you know, learn from the mistake. So
far, so good. You know, it's it's just
really worked as a very empowering um
environment. It is true that I can press
the the reset button whenever you know,
is necessary or whenever it feels right.
And, you know, that's like it that's a
privilege. Uh and also, it allows me to,
you know, just really be close to the
community in ways that I think, you
know, would not be otherwise possible,
right? I don't have to run it, you know,
through an echelon of approvals.
>> You said sometimes people screw up. Is
there something you screwed up in that
in that I don't know, that the amount of
autonomy and trust you have, something
you messed up?
>> Yes, I I think at times um I could have,
you know, made
teams like, you know, more inspired to
build like things that are less complex
uh and just really continue to strive
towards uh complexity.
I think we, you know, we early days uh
in Codex, you know, we had, you know, a
couple of like outages that I caused.
Very very early early is for me at
OpenAI. I took production down like day
three. You know, I just
I was still employed after that. Um and
I learned my lesson.
>> One of the other questions people wanted
me to ask you is how many resets should
they expect in the next, I don't know,
month or week?
>> Depends on times you break things.
>> Okay, so that's the philosophy. Break
something you reset. That's kind of a
>> Yeah, break something, celebrate things.
So maybe zoom in a little bit.
What do you think people aren't pricing
in in terms of where things are going
and what will change that they're not
just like seeing as clearly as they
should?
>> There are so many so many things that I
feel are not yet priced in.
I think the majority of actions on the
internet will be taken by agents. Models
are going to become more cheaper and
faster at rates
that are quite incredible. We will
finally be able to integrate all
modalities together in a way that is
very seamless.
I think, you know, those three I feel
like you know, often when I look at what
people are building out there it's just
like not, you know, just like you're not
quite getting it. It's like you know,
you're almost there but like you know,
if you were just like pushing yourself
and just really imagining like all of
this being roughly 10 times better than
it is today, you know, like in a year.
It's like, you know, you would build in
a different way.
>> Do you see any kind of second order
effects that come from that from this
world where most actions are being Uh
from agents. Agents are probably most
traffic's going to come from agents. I
don't know.
>> That's right.
>> You think about some second order effect
that emerges out of that?
>> Yeah, there there there there are many.
Um you know, for for first of all, you
know, if you want your product to be
successful for agents, you know, it's
like you have to build you know, for a
certain level of scale.
Um we've worked very closely with Notion
for example and like when they build
their MCP, you know, suddenly it's like,
oh well, you know, it's available to all
these agents that you know, can actually
do do the work and like use that MCP and
so they saw like
a ton of traffic kind of come in. Um and
that puts obviously a lot of strain on
the system and you have to figure out
the economics of that. And so there's
like this tension, you know, between
like you know, if you're building
products is like you know, do you build
an interface or not? And you know, you
can kind of hold that back for a while
but it is inevitable, right? It's like
you know, you're the majority of things
are going to be used by agents. Building
towards that future I think is very
important. The other thing is, you know,
on the flip side, you know, building
like you know, absolutely delightful new
experiences for humans that you know,
really benefit from older modalities is
something that I you know, I feel like
is under invested in.
>> Is there something you've changed your
mind about in the past uh let's say
year? Just something that you used to
believe that
you see differently?
>> I was expecting us to reach
the level of capabilities the of the
models that we have today, you know, say
like Astra, you know, maybe in a year or
two.
Um and so I had to sort of like you
know, revise my my prior order.
Also,
I did not expect to rely so much on
voice.
Um
and you know, I do so much through
dictation or just calling my agent.
And I had not anticipated that, you
know, how much
how much better that feels. So like I I
had to change my mind there. And then,
you know, you talked about hiring and
you know, one thing that I hadn't
realized is like
the incredible talent and energy and you
know, the just you younger generations
have um and how they would be the ones
embracing like all this change first and
like figure out how to harness, you
know, all of it. And so, you know, I had
to change also my opinion on the hiring
and the strategy there.
>> The just to double down on that, just
this idea that new people new in the
workforce actually have an advantage
because they haven't worked in a certain
way and they could just go all in on AI.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I think I just also the
ability to just like absorb and learn
like super fast.
>> So you talked about models getting
really smart fast.
Uh obviously there's a lot of discussion
these days about what AI can do in the
future, the dangers AI poses to humans,
P doom, and all these things.
Uh you guys have slowed down some
training. Uh you guys everyone's pacing
the frontier. How do you think about
this world of AI and the potential risk
to the humans? How do you think about
that?
>> For me like pacing the frontier is just
really investing ahead, right? And also
investing way more, you know, than we
even think, you know, like we ought to.
Uh investing in the alignment and safety
of the models, investing in uh security,
investing in the guardrails. We are
spending more and more compute on sort
of like secondary monitoring. So, you
have you know, you have all of the
computer that's going to the primary
system, you know, the agent that is like
doing work. And then you have all of the
computer that's going into monitoring,
you know, the primary agent to make sure
that it's like not taking too high risk
of actions or like not interrupting it
if anything looks like you know, maybe
it's getting prompt injected and just
like you know, intervening with that.
And the majority of our investment on
the API stack is like not actually going
into the safety stack. And so to me, you
know, that is pacing. It's like you
know, you want to make sure that you
know, you're extremely hardened. That's
what we're doing. Like we haven't yet
released the next step up in capability
beyond Astra. Um we have released, you
know, a level that is like similar, near
Astra intelligence, but like you know,
much more efficient. And so we feel very
comfortable about that. But we're going
to continue to like invest a ton there.
And I feel uh I feel very good um about
our approach so far. Um I think you
know, it's like it was also in the news
that you know, we had six one Astra and
then we didn't release it. Um and that
is something I'm very proud of.
>> So, what I'm hearing is you're
optimistic we will
solve these problems of alignment and AI
doing really bad things. AI's been doing
a lot of really really s-
not good things lately with hugging face
and all that stuff. But what I'm hearing
is
uh optimistic we'll solve it. It'll be
all right.
>> Yes. And it's also it's it's I feel, you
know, obviously a deep responsibility,
but also just, you know, if you think
about the incentives for OpenAI, right?
you know, we build products for 1.2
billion people. We can't screw that up.
Right? You know, we take it very very
seriously. Um what we put in the hands
of so many people, you know, including
people who are not very technical
themselves, you know, you have to get it
right. And so, you know, we we don't
gamble there.
>> Final question.
Uh uh
What's something that annoys you about
the current state of the app that you're
just like, "God damn it, we got to fix
that."
Uh current state of the app. Um
I feel like the the the models are
almost there, but not quite for the app
to almost completely disappear. And you
know, I can't wait for you know, to just
really get to this like super essence of
simplicity. I myself even get fatigued
with the model picker and the reasoning
efforts and you know, whether to use
multi-agent or ultra or you know, what
it even does and you kind of need a PhD
in model pickers.
Right?
Um and I just want to get rid of all of
that
um as quickly as we can.
>> Amazing.
Ebo, thanks for doing this.
>> Yeah, thanks for having me. Yeah.
>> Thank you so much for listening. If you
found this valuable, you can subscribe
to the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
or your favorite podcast app.
Also, please consider giving us a rating
or leaving a review as that really helps
other listeners find the podcast. You
can find all past episodes or learn more
about the show at lennyspodcast.com.
See you in the next episode.